Ajay Kumar

Jamshedpur, Jharkhand ajaykumar69946_dkn@indeedemail.com +91 98931 49123

Intend to build a career with leading corporate of hi-tech environment with committed & dedicated people, which will help me to explore myself fully and realize my potential. Willing to work as a key player in challenging & creative environment.

Research Interest: Infectious diseases, molecular epidemiology, genomics, proteomics and host pathogen interactions. Development of biomarkers-based assays for diagnosis of infectious diseases.

Work Experience

Assistant Professor

Manipal TATA Medical College - Jamshedpur, Jharkhand November 2022 to Present

Tutor in Department of Microbiology

Manipal TATA Medical College - Jamshedpur, Jharkhand February 2020 to October 2022

lecturer in Department of Microbiology

Bhabha College of Dental Sciences - Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh January 2010 to August 2013

TRAINING & CERTIFICATE COURSES

- ♦ Completed certificate course on whole genome sequencing of bacterial genomes- tools and applications authorized by Technical University of Denmark.
- ♦ Completed certificate course on Antimicrobial resistance- theory and methods authorized by Technical University of Denmark.
- ♦ Completed ISO 15189:2012 IA & OMS Certificate Course organized by Medical Education & Learning Point, New Delhi
- ♦ Completed NPTEL online certification course "Basic Course in Biomedical Research" offered by National Institute of Epidemiology, Indian Council of Medical Research, Chennai.
- ♦ Completed NPTEL online certification course "Health Research Fundamentals" offered by National Institute of Epidemiology, Indian Council of Medical Research, Chennai.
- ♦ Completed NPTEL online certification course "Experimental Biotechnology" coordinated by Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati.
- ♦ Completed NPTEL online certification course "Introduction to Proteomics" coordinated by Indian Institute of Technology Bombay.
- ♦ Completed Certificate course "Bioinformatics Methods and Tools Master" from Biotecnika Info Labs
- ♦ Carried out 1-year Dissertation project work at National JALMA Institute for Leprosy & Other Mycobacterial Diseases (ICMR), Tajganj, Agra on Project entitled "Serological studies with leprosy patients employing various Mycobacterium leprae antigens".

Education

PhD in Medical Microbiology

Santosh Medical College, Santosh University - Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh $2020\,$

M.Sc. in Medical Microbiology

Bundelkhand University - Jhansi, Uttar Pradesh 2006

B.Sc. in Pathology

Barkatullah University - Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh 2004

Skills / IT Skills

- Fundamentals, Basic, MS WORD, EXCEL, and Internet. STRENGHTS
- Quick Learner, Collaborative, Decisive thinker, driven to deliver.